<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Vinícius Mioto</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/icon_hu10762989417876225641.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Game Testing</title>
      <link>/project/automated_game_testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/automated_game_testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the gaming industry grows, there is a greater need for high-quality, complex games, which requires efficient and scalable testing methods. This paper maps recording-based game test automation tools that record and replay user actions to make testing easier and reduce manual work. We analyzed 20 tools mentioned in industry blogs and grouped them into game-specific and general-purpose categories. We also evaluated their compatibility, input simulation features, scripting options, and integration with game engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our findings indicate that general-purpose tools, the most frequently mentioned in blog sources, offer broad adaptability across platforms but are typically limited to user interface and visual testing. In contrast, game-specific tools provide deeper integration with game engines, supporting access to in-game mechanics and making them better suited for testing gameplay aspects. Our observations intend to conduct industry and academic efforts toward more reliable, scalable, and cost-effective approaches to automated game testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advisor&#34;&gt;Advisor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fabiopetrillo.com&#34;&gt;Fabio Petrillo, Ph.D.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Network Analysis</title>
      <link>/project/network_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/network_analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started this undergraduate research project in 2021 by studying the paper &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5753/eniac.2019.9319&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Recognizing Power-law Graphs by Machine Learning Algorithms using a Reduced Set of Structural Features&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, the authors &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inf.ufpr.br/amlima/&#34;&gt;Alane Marie de Lima&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inf.ufpr.br/vignatti/&#34;&gt;André Luis Vignatti&lt;/a&gt; were my advisors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, as my final project for the BSc. in CS, I am researching about &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2402.14367&#34;&gt;Representation Learning for Frequent Subgraph Mining&lt;/a&gt; paper. The motivation for this study came from classes of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.stanford.edu/class/cs224w/&#34;&gt;ML with Graphs course&lt;/a&gt; offered by Stanford University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advisors&#34;&gt;Advisors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inf.ufpr.br/vignatti/&#34;&gt;André Luís Vignatti&lt;/a&gt;, PhD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;experiments&#34;&gt;Experiments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/viniciusmioto/social_networks_analysis&#34;&gt;Repository (GitHub)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
